Finding Aid of America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee Record Group SR.198
State Archives of North Carolina
- Logo File, 1983-1987; SR.198.6; 198.6; 4044; Agreements; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources
  RS No. 4044
  - Advisory Committee for Sale of Products, 1980, 1982-1983, undated; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Advisory Committee for Sale of Products)
  - Agency East: License Agreements, 1983, undated; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Agency East: License Agreements)
  - Agency East: Swearington Correspondence, 1983-1985, undated; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Agency East: Swearington Correspondence)
  - Certificate of Registration, 1981, 1985; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Certificate of Registration)
  - General Correspondence, 1983-1984, 1986, undated; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder General Correspondence)
  - Licensing Agents Correspondence, 1982-1983, undated; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Licensing Agents Correspondence)
  - Request for Logo Use: Commercial Use Request, 1982-1983, undated; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Request for Logo Use: Commercial Use Request)
  - Request for Logo Use: Non-Commercial Use Request, 1981-1985; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Request for Logo Use: Non-Commercial Use Request)
  - Trademark Registration, 1980-1985; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Trademark Registration)
  - Visuals, 1983-1984, 1986, undated; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Visuals)
  - William A. Ries and Associates Advertising, 1983, undated; SR.198.6.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder William A. Ries and Associates Advertising)
- Elizabeth II File, 1982-1987; SR.198.7; 198.7; 4045; Drawings Photographs; 1.00; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources
  Drawings, state bid information, photographs, slides, correspondence, feasibility reports, contracts, memorandums, and research file concerning the planning, construction, launching, and dedication of Elizabeth II and historic site at Shallowbag Bay in Manteo. Elizabeth II was the brainchild of former Governor James B. Hunt, Jr. that was designed by late William Avery Baker and Stanley Potter. The ship replica was completed in early 1984 by the O. Lie-Nielsen, a shipbuilder located in Rockland, Maine.
  RS No. 4045
  - Agreements, 1985; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Agreements)
  - Bid Contracts and Invitation, 1982, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Bid Contracts and Invitation)
  - Boathouse Construction, 1982, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Boathouse Construction)
  - Brochure, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Brochure)
  - Channel Dredging, 1983-1985; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Channel Dredging)
  - Charlestowne Landing: The Adventure of the Carolinas, 1983-1984, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Charlestowne Landing: The Adventure of the Carolinas)
  - Correspondence: Construction, 1980-1982, 1985, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: Construction)
  - Correspondence: General Correspondence, 1978-1983, 1985, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Correspondence: General Correspondence)
  - Dedication Ceremony of Keel and Frame, 1982, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Dedication Ceremony of Keel and Frame)
  - Description and Illustrations, 1984, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Description and Illustrations)
  - East Carolina Report (Horace Whitfield II), January 1985; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder East Carolina Report (Horace Whitfield II))
  - Educational Activities: SubCommittee, 1980-1985, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Educational Activities: SubCommittee)
  - Friends of Elizabeth II, 1981-1984, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Friends of Elizabeth II)
  - Golden Hinde: Sir Humphrey Gilbert Quadricentennial, 1982, undated; SR.198.7.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Golden Hinde: Sir Humphrey Gilbert Quadricentennial)
  - Historic Site: Office, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Historic Site: Office)
  - Historic Site: Visitor Center Construction, 1981-1982; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Historic Site: Visitor Center Construction)
  - Launching of Elizabeth II: Fish Fry Guest List, 22 November 1983; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Launching of Elizabeth II: Fish Fry Guest List)
  - Launching of Elizabeth II: General Correspondence, 1983; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Launching of Elizabeth II: General Correspondence)
  - Launching of Elizabeth II: Publicity for Launch, 1983; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Launching of Elizabeth II: Publicity for Launch)
  - Lee-Nielsen, O. (Builder), 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Lee-Nielsen, O. (Builder))
  - Maritime Preservation Grants Program, 1978-1981, undated; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Maritime Preservation Grants Program)
  - Maryland Dove, 1973, 1975, 1977, undated; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Maryland Dove)
  - Mary Rose Trust (U.K.), 1982-1983, undated; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Mary Rose Trust (U.K.))
  - Mayflower II, undated; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Mayflower II)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981-1983, 1985-1986, undated; SR.198.7.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Miscellaneous)
  - Photography of Elizabeth II: Bell, 1984, undated; SR.198.7.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Photography of Elizabeth II: Bell)
  - Photography of Elizabeth II: Project, circa 1981-1983; SR.198.7.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Photography of Elizabeth II: Project)
  - Plans of Elizabeth II, 1981-1982; SR.198.7.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Plans of Elizabeth II)
  - Potter, Stanley: Correspondence, 1981-1984; SR.198.7.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Potter, Stanley: Correspondence)
  - Potter, Stanley: Request for Payments/Expenses, 1981-1983; SR.198.7.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Potter, Stanley: Request for Payments/Expenses)
  - Research and Feasibility, 1981-1982, undated; SR.198.7.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Research and Feasibility)
  - Shipbuilders, 1981-1982, undated; SR.198.7.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Shipbuilders)
  - Tall Ships, 1981-1984, 1986, undated; SR.198.7.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Tall Ships)
- Assistant Director's Office County File, 1982-1987; SR.198.8; 198.9; 4047; Correspondence; 2.00; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources
  General correspondence, county correspondence and information, and workshop material related to the committee's work.
  RS No. 4047
  - Alamance, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Alamance)
  - Alexander, 1982-1987, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Alexander)
  - Alleghany, 1984, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Alleghany)
  - Anson, 1982-1986, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Anson)
  - Ashe, 1983, 1985; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Ashe)
  - Avery, 1982,1984-1985, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Avery)
  - Beaufort, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Beaufort)
  - Bertie, 1982-1983, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Bertie)
  - Bladen, 1982-1983, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Bladen)
  - Brunswick, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Brunswick)
  - Buncombe, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Buncombe)
  - Burke, 1982-1985; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Burke)
  - Cabarrus, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Cabarrus)
  - Caldwell, 1982, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Caldwell)
  - Camden, 1982-1984; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Camden)
  - Carteret, 1982-1986, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Carteret)
  - Caswell, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Caswell)
  - Catawba, 1982-1985, 1987, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Catawba)
  - Chatham, 1982, 1984; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Chatham)
  - Cherokee, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Cherokee)
  - Chowan, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Chowan)
  - Clay, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Clay)
  - Cleveland, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Cleveland)
  - Columbus, 1982, 1984, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Columbus)
  - Craven, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.001; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Craven)
  - Cumberland: General Correspondence, 1973, 1982-1986, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Cumberland: General Correspondence)
  - Cumberland: Fayetteville Little Theater, 1973, 1982; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Cumberland: Fayetteville Little Theater)
  - Currituck, 1983-1984, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Currituck)
  - Dare, 1981-1984, 1986, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Dare)
  - Davidson, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Davidson)
  - Davie, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Davie)
  - Duplin, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Duplin)
  - Durham, 1982-1983, 1985-1986, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Durham)
  - Edgecombe, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Edgecombe)
  - Forsyth, 1982-1986, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Forsyth)
  - Franklin, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Franklin)
  - Gaston, 1982-1986, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Gaston)
  - Gates, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Gates)
  - Graham, 1982, 1984, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Graham)
  - Granville, 1982, 1984-1985, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Granville)
  - Greene, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Greene)
  - Guilford, 1982-1984, 1986-1987, undated; SR.198.8.002; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Guilford)
  - Halifax, 1983-1984, 1986, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Halifax)
  - Harnett, 1984-1985, 1987, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Harnett)
  - Haywood, 1982-1984, 1987; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Haywood)
  - Henderson, 1983-1985; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Henderson)
  - Hertford, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Hertford)
  - Hoke, 1982; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Hoke)
  - Hyde, 1982-1985; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Hyde)
  - Iredell, 1982-1986, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Iredell)
  - Jackson, 1982-1984; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Jackson)
  - Johnston, 1982-1984; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Johnston)
  - Jones, 1982-1984; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Jones)
  - Lee, 1982-1983, 1985, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Lee)
  - Lenoir, 1983-1984, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Lenoir)
  - Lincoln, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Lincoln)
  - Macon, 1982, 1984; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Macon)
  - Madison, 1982, 1984; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Madison)
  - Martin, 1982, 1984; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Martin)
  - McDowell, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder McDowell)
  - Mecklenburg, 1982-1987, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Mecklenburg)
  - Mitchell, 1982-1986, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Mitchell)
  - Montgomery, 1982-1983; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Montgomery)
  - Moore, 1982-1987, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Moore)
  - Nash, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Nash)
  - New Hanover, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.003; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder New Hanover)
  - Northampton, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Northampton)
  - Onslow: General Correspondence, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Onslow: General Correspondence)
  - Onslow: "Seminar on Onslow County History", 1982; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Onslow: "Seminar on Onslow County History")
  - Orange, 1982-1986, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Orange)
  - Pamlico, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Pamlico)
  - Pasquotank: General Correspondence, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Pasquotank: General Correspondence)
  - Pasquotank: Salmons Teacher's Guide, 1984; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Pasquotank: Salmons Teacher's Guide)
  - Pender, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Pender)
  - Perquimans, 1982-1986, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Perquimans)
  - Person, 1982, 1984; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Person)
  - Pitt: General Correspondence, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Pitt: General Correspondence)
  - Pitt: East Carolina Meeting Materials, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Pitt: East Carolina Meeting Materials)
  - Polk, 1982-1984; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Polk)
  - Randolph, 1982-1987, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Randolph)
  - Richmond, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Richmond)
  - Robeson, 1982-1983, 1986, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Robeson)
  - Rockingham, 1982-1985; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Rockingham)
  - Rowan, 1982-1985, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Rowan)
  - Rutherford, 1982-1984, undated; SR.198.8.004; Department of Natural and Cultural Resources. America's Four Hundredth Anniversary Committee (Folder Rutherford)